Mss.Rec.9 Mss.Rec.9
American Philosophical Society
Tuscarora Indian Material
1950-1951
Mss.Rec.9
American Philosophical Society
6.0 Reel(s)
Recorded at the Tuscarora Reservation in Niagara County, New York from December 1950 to January 1951. Consists of Tuscarora vocabulary, paradigms, and stories regarding tribal history told in Tuscarora only.
6 sound tape reels (3 hr., 14 min.): analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track, mono; 7 in.
Johnson, Art
Reyburn, William D.
Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by William Reyburn in 1951. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Materials
Translations and transcriptions can be found in the Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics collection (Mss.497.3.B63c).
Indian Defense League of America; Indians of North America--Migrations; Migration, Internal--United States--History--19th century; Military service, Voluntary--United States; Six Nations--History; Sound recordings; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language
- Audio recordings
  - Tuscarora vocabulary, 1950-12-24; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:15; Johnson, Arthur; Reyburn, William D.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Tuscarora vocabulary and paradigms [1 of 4], 1950-12-27; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:19; Reyburn, William D.; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
  - Tuscarora vocabulary and paradigms [2 of 4], 1950-12-27; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:23; Reyburn, William D.; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
  - Tuscarora vocabulary and paradigms [3 of 4], 1951-01-01; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:20; Reyburn, William D.; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
  - Tuscarora vocabulary and paradigms [4 of 4], 1951-01-04; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:21; Reyburn, William D.; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
  - A Tuscarora text, 1951-01-08; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:43; Reyburn, William D.; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
    Scope and Contents note
    Topic of text unclear from documentation. May be about the Salt War in New York State. In Tuscarora only.
  - The participation of the Tuscaroras in the War of 1812, 1951-01-08; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:26; Reyburn, William D.; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
    In Tuscarora only.
    Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); United States--History--War of 1812
  - The enlistment in Philadelphia of a group of Tuscarora soldiers, 1951-01-08; 06-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:19; Reyburn, William D.; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
    Military service, Voluntary--United States; Recruiting and enlistment; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - The trip of the Tuscaroras to Kansas and the subsequent activities of the informant's grandfather and Captain Kyusik with a group of Sioux Indians following the Mexican War, 1951-01-08; 06-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:17; Reyburn, William D.; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
    Narrative told in Tuscarora only.
    Dakota Indians; Indians of North America--Migrations; Migration, Internal--United States--History--19th century; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
  - How Washington appealed to the Iroquois Nation to aid the Thirteen Colonies in the Revolutionary War; Promises made by General Washington to the Six Nations, 1951-01-08; 06-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:14; Reyburn, William D.; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
    Six Nations--History; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.); United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783; Washington, George, 1732-1799--Relations with Indians
  - The story of the Indian Defense League of America, 1951-01-08; 06-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:29; Reyburn, William D.; Rickard, Clinton, 1882-1971
    The speaker was a Grand President of the Indian Defense League of America. In Tuscarora only.
    Indian Defense League of America; Tuscarora Indians--History; Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)